Now we already prepared some things for production,
let me now dive into that secure headers thing and for that, we'll use a third party package which is called
helmet and you can use it to secure your node express applications.
Now you can dive into the official docs of this package to learn more about it
and in the end what this will do is this package will add certain headers to the responses you sent
back and it follows best practices for doing so,
you'll see which attack patterns or which security issues these are against which it protects you by
setting the right headers.
So definitely check that out to learn more about these headers and why it protects you against that,
using the package
is very easy though.
In your project, you just run and install --save helmet and then this will be downloaded and
you can use it as you see here by simply including it as a middleware and then it will automatically
run on all incoming requests and therefore also have a chance of adjusting the responses as you
learned
and it will then set its headers. So you can simply go to your app.js file then and there, import helmet
by requiring it like this
and then as a next step, you simply add this line here after you initialized your express app, maybe
in the place where we then also set up all our other middleware down there.
Here we can use app use helmet and execute this as a function, and this is it.
Now with that, if I run npm run start:dev, my new script I added to use nodemon,
everything runs as before but now actually if I visit localhost 3000 here and I hope my network tab
and I reload this page, I can see that on this response, I have a couple of headers being set and there are
some special headers which were added by helmet here and you can always check that by temporarily commenting
out helmet, we'll automatically restart since I'm using nodemon,
we had 11 response headers before, if I now reload this,
we just have 6 because now some special headers are missing.
And that is something you should consider doing,
read through the official docs to learn all about the headers
it is adding but it's definitely worth looking at that and probably worth using that.